SEAN KING

<u>seapat22.github.io</u>Willoughby, Ohio

seanking2224@gmail.com

DATA / SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dependable, hard worker with a strong work ethic. Knowledge of and experienced in various programming languages and agile development methodologies. Problem solving skills and ability to break down complex problems and find solutions both by myself and in scrum teams. Able to adapt and learn new technologies in various fields like data analytics and software engineering.

EDUCATION:

Kent State University

Kent, OH

Cell: (440) 376-1120

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science August 2020 – May 2023

Graduated in three (3) years Cum Laude with GPA 3.613

PREVIOUS PROJECTS:

• Enhanced Snake Game

Developed an enhanced version of the classic game, Snake, which includes: A new difficulty component that can increase or decrease the difficulty of the game Developed using C++

• Kent State University Fencing Club Website

Developed a website for the fencing club at Kent State University
Included: calendar for events, member information page, and a merchandise page
Developed using PHP, HTML, and JavaScript

• Online Multiplayer Left Right Center Game

Created an online version of the game: Left Right Center Included an online multi-player component Developed using **Python** and **JavaScript**

WORK EXPERIENCE:

The Irish American Club – East Side – Bartender

Euclid, OH

December 2024 – Present

- Prepare, mix and serves a multitude of drink and food orders
- Communication with patrons and exceptional customer interaction
- Handles cash, operates POS system, and maintains honest and accurate transactions
- Manages bar inventory, order supplies, stock and organize supplies
- Train new bartenders and other staff members
- Adheres to all alcohol service regulations, health and safety standards
- Maintains a clean and sanitary bar

Kent State University – Resident Assistant (RA)

Kent, OH

August 2021 – December 2021

• Provided a resource for dorm residents – offering information and referrals to campus services

- Monitored the dorm to ensure compliance with policies
- Respectfully responded to and resolved complaints
- Support to dorm residents 24/7
- Fostered community and personal growth to dorm residents

Firehouse Subs - Floor Staff

Willoughby, OH July 2018 thru October 2018

- Helped customers as they placed orders
- Accurately prepared orders and received cash/credit/digital payments
- Assisted with inventory management as well as stock shelves, and maintained a clean and organized store
- Positively assisted disgruntled customers with incorrect orders and/or complaints

CERTIFICATIONS:

• **OSHA**: 10-hour general industry

• **TestOut**: PC Pro

• **TestOut**: Desktop Pro

• Microsoft: Foundational C#

SKILLS:

- Web Design and Programming (C++, C#, Python, JavaScript, PHP, HTML/CSS)
- Software Development Life Cycle
- Agile Methodologies
- Source Control (Git)
- Oracle VM Virtual Box
- Data Analysis and Database Design (R, MySQL, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn)
- Windows
- Linux
- Scrum Teams
- Visual Studio